you guys welcome to another video of the new session that could be a different evasion
tactics for most of the time the yes the threat factors they will be get caught easily
in the when they are trying to do any kind of different activations because if they tried
to uninstall the EER are anywhere to software so at that time the latest EER has a behavior
based rule if someone tries to uninstall it will trigger a detections okay but you need
to think about if you you need to carefully develop a program or develop a shell code or
some some kind of malicious script that could bypass the antivirus of where even if it
was installed okay installed and the program was running the antivirus program was running
we have did a plenty of research and we have find one of the method that has bypassed
the McAfee antivirus software so this machine also I have a McAfee Postman security
is plus McAfee or trial also every Windows Defender services has been turned on and
it was working fine the tool which we are going to use that was the cobalt strike for
a macro based creation so you know this console if you click on the payload or you can
see a mass of this macro for many of them have a doubt on this how to generate how
the threat types will be generating the macro enable document basically the macro enable
document you should know like the TAs will be developing some kind of macro based execution
scripts so they will be embedding the malicious script into some kind of documents or
actually actual sharp points and they will be delivering that through email or some we are link
okay so once the user or the customers they get clicked on that the the the macro and
the per document will be basically it will get opened so in the backend the malicious
script get automatic like script okay so we will see how to how to do that thing so I was
choosing the macro based mal this simple HTTP based original so I will be choosing this
if you see this one if you copy the macro the macro has been automatically copied then
you need to go to the target window you need a Windows Windows machine to create a macro
based document so once you once you go for a macro based type something like so if you
sending any kind of phishing later the documents to anyone so you need to be you need to
be carefully write the document this could be look like a legitimate one so that only
the user or the customer they will be clicked on that and in the background to be get
executed so this could be like a legitimate one so in front of like you can send some gift
or some kind of resume or some kind of invoice bills or something so you can type some invoice
bill so this could be an example which I'm saying okay so once you prepared the the
document then go to BU so here you can find the BU macro so just click on the macro just
click on create sorry you need to give a name so I'll be selecting my name and so it will
be opening a small macro code okay so I'll say on thing about the macro based one so the
Microsoft developed the macro for automating the task okay basically if you see the Excel
sheet there is a lot of data and a lot of call and still be present so the programmers they'll
be writing some kind of automation scripts in the macro and they'll be giving it to the
other user so once the other employees or other users visiting or visiting or opening
the document they can BU the automated format okay so for that only the macro get macro
because it has been developed by the Microsoft team okay so basically it will be automating
the task that's the important purpose that the main purpose of the macro based thing okay
so that's all you need to replace you need to copy paste the entire script here okay
so then you can save it as a normal and import a file and you can save the entire document
save you can save somewhere okay macro one two or something okay so listen when the user
when the user opened the macro enable document and here it was not so in enabling editing
or something so the user will be the user will be automatically get executed okay the
macro file get automatically executed he see here so when I just opened this document and
I didn't give anything here run or anything I didn't test anything but I opened the
document right so at that time I got a remote connection here let me show you here interact
so if I do the ears so let's wait for our result I didn't click on any kind of thing
I just opened the document macro we have created before macro 2 and suddenly some reverse
connections get initiated see the next one right so see it was coming from the rendial
32.exe so we can believe something some code get injected into the rendial 30.exe and
we got a reverse connections from there so this is one of a powerful mechanism that will
be bypassing the windows defenders and the Macafee antivirus officer so we will be
easily getting a reverse connection from there okay so the macro is one of a very very
powerful mechanism to get a C2 connection so many of the organization that has been compromised
through the phishing documents and the phishing outlook based messages so this is one
of very easy and very very sensitive kind of initial access because the EDS and antivirus
officers do not have a capability to stop this kind of phishing related activities the
email looks like a legitimate one the domain looks like legitimate one the demorticity of
everything will be find at that time so the EDS will be also get confused as it's
a legitimate or malicious email so the idea will think like it's it's a legitimate
email and it will allow that emails once the user we've clicked on that document so
suddenly the malicious script the macro get executed in the back end he know when we opened
the macro to which we which we have created I didn't get any kind of CMD prompt or I didn't
get any kind of third party applications or anything get loaded there's nothing I just
opened the document I can I can see the screen the document screen but there is nothing
get loaded and no applications has been triggered or anything the user don't know anything
what happening but silently there will be a reverse connection such thing going on
there right so I hope you have a clear understanding about how we needs to create a macro
and how macro will be powerful to get an initial access okay and the different situation
techniques so I hope you have a clear understanding about this one
be will be will be meet in the next video thanks bye bye